OK  so you got a new sweater
好，所以你买了件新毛衣？
it looks great
看起来很棒
and you're getting tons of compliments  but then
你得到了很多赞美，但是
just one person says something snarky about it
只有一个人说些尖刻的话
and even though you got all that praise
即使你得到了所有的赞美
you can't help but stew over the negative comment
你不禁为负面评论而烦恼
why is that
那是为什么呢？
why does our mind seem to dwell on the negative
为什么我们的思想似乎停留在消极的一面
a lot of my research focuses on how people
我的很多研究都集中在人们如何
tend to get stuck in particular ways of
倾向于以特定的方式卡住
thinking and what enables them to get unstuck
思考以及是什么让他们摆脱困境
Allison Ledgerwood is a psychology professor at uc Davis
艾莉森·莱杰伍德是加州大学戴维斯分校的心理学教授
i get to study how humans think and
我可以研究人类如何思考
how we could maybe think better
我们怎样才能想得更好
we all know the expression about seeing a
我们都知道看到一个
glass as half full or half empty
半满或半空的杯子
it isn't just what you see
这不仅仅是你看到的
but how you see it
但是你怎么看呢？
and the way you describe that glass to people
你向人们描述那个杯子的方式
can really change how they feel about it
能真正改变他们的感受
Allison wanted to know what happens when you
艾莉森想知道当你
try to switch your way of thinking from the
试着把你的思维方式从
positive frame to the negative frame
正帧到负帧
or vice versa
反之亦然
her research team brought two groups of people into the
她的研究小组带了两组人进入
lab and told them about a new surgical procedure
告诉他们一种新的外科手术
group one was told that the procedure
第一组被告知程序
has a seventy percent success rate
有百分之七十的成功率
for group two
对于第二组
they framed it as a thirty percent failure rate
他们认为失败率为30%
it's the same exact procedure and they're
这是完全相同的程序，他们
giving you the exact same information
给你完全相同的信息
but one doctor is focusing on the
但是一位医生正在关注
part of the glass that's full
满的杯子的一部分
and the other doctor is focusing on
另一个医生专注于
the part of the glass that's empty
杯子是空的部分
so no surprise
所以没什么好惊讶的
people like the procedure when it's
人们喜欢这个程序
described in positive terms
正面描述
and they don't like it when you focus on the failure rate
他们不喜欢你关注失败率
but then the researchers pointed it out to the first
但是后来研究人员指出了第一个
group that you could also think of the
你也可以想到的组
procedure as failing thirty percent of the time  suddenly
程序有30%的时间突然失败
people didn't like it anymore
人们不再喜欢它了
二十五的效率高的人
会在每天的开始就把
当天要做的事情列出来
然后按照重要性和紧急性排序
再把它们分成几个小的任务
然后逐个完成
这样做的好处是可以让你更
清楚地知道自己要做什么
避免浪费时间和精力
so once you frame something negatively
所以一旦你把某件事定为负面
it really sticks
它真的很粘
it makes sense from an evolutionary or functional
从进化或功能上讲，这是有意义的
perspective that our minds are built to look for negative
我们的大脑是为了寻找消极的观点
information in the environment and to hold on to it once we
环境中的信息，一旦我们
find it
找到它
imagine your prehistoric ancestors
想象一下你的史前祖先
you don't want to forget that there
你不会想忘记的
might be a predator lurking around
可能有个掠食者潜伏在附近
in many situations
在许多情况下
we want our minds to be grabbed
我们希望我们的思想被抓住
by the negative information
通过负面信息
so that we can fix problems when they're there
这样我们就可以在他们出现时解决问题
but then
但是后来
there are other situations where we want to get over
还有其他情况我们想克服
some small imperfection or a bit of bad news
一些小瑕疵或一点坏消息
when it's not helpful to fixate on the negative
当关注消极的事情没有帮助的时候
what do we do then
那我们怎么办？
what i really take away from this research for my own
我从这项研究中真正学到的是
life is that it's difficult to see the upside
生活就是很难看到好的一面
and that it takes work  literally
从字面上看，这需要工作。
that we have to put effort into
我们必须付出努力
looking at the bright side of things
看到事物光明的一面
that we can't assume that our mind is
我们不能假设我们的大脑
just going to do that automatically
只是要自动这样做
and that it's very easy to just keep
而且很容易保持
tilting back towards the negatives
向底片倾斜
and this is something you can counteract with practice
这是你可以通过练习来抵消的。
like spending a few minutes each day thinking
比如每天花几分钟思考
about the things you're grateful for
关于你感激的事情
doing this regularly can help it become a habit
经常这样做可以帮助它成为一种习惯
and it turns out that this negative bias can change
事实证明，这种负面偏见可以改变
over time remember when you were younger and any bad
随着时间的推移，记得你年轻的时候和任何不好的时候
experience felt like the end of the world
经历就像世界末日
so this kind of pervasive
所以这种无孔不入
negativity bias starts to diminish
消极偏见开始减少
and so in our research we find that the stickiness
在我们的研究中我们发现粘度
of a negative frame seems to disappear entirely by
的负帧似乎完全消失了
the time people are in their seventies
人们七十多岁的时候
they seem to flow back and forth between
它们似乎在两者之间来回流动
negatives and positives much more easily
消极和积极更容易
so maybe that's something we can all be grateful for
所以也许这是我们都应该感激的事情
that there are actually some good
实际上有一些好的
things about getting older
关于变老的事情
how do you get out of negative ways of thinking
你如何摆脱消极的思维方式？
let us know in the comments below
请在下面的评论中告诉我们
and be sure to check out our other
一定要看看我们的另一个
video all about the teenage brain
关于青少年大脑的视频
remembering all the things you did as
记得你做过的所有事情
a teenager might make you cringe
青少年可能会让你畏缩
neuroscientists are learning that some of the most puzzling
神经科学家正在研究一些最令人费解的
teenage behavior may actually serve an evolutionary purpose
青少年的行为可能实际上服务于进化的目的